houseandhome.com 2017-03-09

# Consumer Privacy Statement - House & Home

House & Home Media (“HHM”) is committed to preserving and safeguarding your right to privacy, and complying with the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (“PIPEDA”) and applicable provincial privacy legislation. We have prepared this Privacy Statement to let you know about the manner in which we collect, use, disclose and otherwise manage the personal information you entrust to us in connection with one of our magazine publications, Canadian House & Home or Maison & Demeure (the “HHM Magazine”), and the corresponding website located at houseandhome.com or maisonetdemeure.com (the “Website”).

## Collection And Use Of Personal Information

We may collect personal information that you provide us when you:

### Subscribe for a HHM Magazine, or manage your subscription on the Website

When you subscribe for a HHM Magazine (personal or gift), we may collect your name, mailing address, e-mail address and credit card or other payment information for the purposes of fulfilling your subscription, sending you invoices, and contacting you prior to (or after) the expiry of your subscription. If you are a subscriber to a HHM Magazine, you may access and update your account information through our Website. You will need your account number or your E-mail address to login.

### Purchase, return, or exchange products offered through the Website

When you purchase products through the Website, we collect your credit information and keep a history of your purchases. We use this information to process your orders, to better assist you when you visit or call us in the future, as well as to improve our product offerings.

When you return previously purchased merchandise or request a refund or exchange, you may be asked to give your name, address, and phone number. We collect this information for fraud prevention purposes.

### Contact our Customer Service department

When you call one of our customer service representatives, or e-mail us with a comment or question you may be asked for information that identifies you, such as your name, address and telephone number, which we need to help us promptly answer your question. We may retain this information to assist you in the future.

## Visit/register with our Website, sign up for an eNewsletter, ask a question of one of our experts through our Website, or participate in a community forum.

**Online Registration:** You do not have to register to browse our Website, but registration is required to access certain features, such as our community forum, or to post user content. Any personal information voluntarily disclosed in our Forums or through other content you post is not governed by this Privacy Statement. When you register, you may be asked for personal information such as your name, gender, age, residential address, e-mail address, and a password that you select. We also offer eNewsletters to those who request this service, and you may be asked for personal information such as your name, e-mail address and a password when you sign up. We use this information to identify who you are and to provide you with the service or information you requested.

**Website information:** We collect the IP (Internet protocol) addresses of all visitors to our Website and other related information such as page requests, browser type, operating system and average time spent on our Website. We use this information to monitor and improve our Website.

Our Website uses a technology called “cookies”. A cookie is a tiny element of data that our Website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive so we can recognize you when you return. If you have registered with our Website, these cookies (1) may let us know who you are and (2) provide us and our service providers with information that we will use to personalize our Site in accordance with your preferences. You may set your Web browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. However, should you decide not to accept cookies from our Website, you may limit the functionality we can provide when you visit.

**Tracer Tags:** Our Website may also use a technology called “tracer tags”. These may also be referred to as “Clear GIFs” or “Web Beacons”. This technology allows us to understand which pages you visit on our Website. These tracer tags are used to help us optimize our Website and provide the best content for you and other future website visitors.

### Enter into a contest or sweepstakes or respond to one of our surveys

When you ask a question, participate in a survey or enter a contest or sweepstakes, we may collect your name, address, phone number and e-mail address. We use this information to administer your participation in the contest or sweepstakes. At the time you are entering a contest or sweepstakes, or completing a survey, we may also obtain your consent for the HHM magazine and/or our marketing partners to send you marketing information in the future.

### eNewsletters

You can unsubscribe from the H&H eNewsletter list at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link provided in each of our eNewsletters, by e-mailing us at [privacy@hhmedia.com](mailto:privacy@hhmedia.com), or by sending us mail to House & Home Media, 511 King Street West, Suite 120, Toronto, ON, M5V 2Z4.

### Provide us with feedback or suggestions

We use your feedback, suggestions, survey information and comments solely to monitor and/or improve the use and features of our Magazine, our Website and our product offerings.

### Disclosure Of Personal Information

HHM will not disclose, transfer, rent, sell or otherwise disclose your personal information, without your prior consent (by way of providing you with an opportunity to opt-out), except as otherwise set out in this Privacy Statement.

### Disclosure to Trading Partners

On occasion, HHM may make its subscriber list available to carefully screened companies whose products and/or service we feel would be of interest to our readers. When you subscribe to a HHM magazine, you will be given the opportunity to opt out of this information sharing arrangement. You may also remove your name from this subscriber promotional list program by contacting us in the manner set out in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

### Disclosure to Service Providers

Certain personal information may be disclosed to third parties solely for the purposes of processing your request or arranging delivery of a product, service or subscription you have requested. HHM may also disclose your personal information to third parties who administer or fulfill contest administration or prize redemption on our behalf. All of our service providers are contractually prohibited from using or disclosing your personal information for any purpose other than providing the services on behalf of HHM.

### Disclosure in Sale of Business

HHM reserves the right to transfer any personal information we have about you in the event we merge, sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets to a third party acquirer.

### Legal Disclosure

HHM must provide your personal information in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry or order, or to an investigative body in the case of a breach of an agreement or contravention of law, or as otherwise required by law. We may also disclose personal information to assist us in collecting a debt owed by you.

### Third Party Links

HHM provides links to third party websites as a convenience to the user. The inclusion of any link does not imply HHM’s endorsement of any other company, its websites, or its products and/or services. These linked websites have separate and independent privacy policies, which we recommend you read carefully. We have no control over such websites and therefore have no responsibility or liability for the manner in which the organizations that operate such linked websites may collect, use, disclose or otherwise treat your personal information.

### Security Of Personal Information

We will maintain the confidentiality of all personal information in our custody and control and will only disclose such information to employees and authorized service providers who require such information for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement. We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure of personal information in our custody and control.

### Passwords

To provide you with an increased level of security, online access to your personal information is protected with a password you select. We strongly recommend that you do not disclose your password to anyone. HHM will never ask you for your password in any unsolicited communication.

### Changes To This Privacy Statement

This privacy statement will be updated periodically to reflect any changes to our personal information practices. We will treat your personal information in accordance with the privacy policy in place at the time of collection of such information, or as you otherwise consent.

### How To Contact Us

We want to assure you that HHM is dedicated to protecting your privacy. Please feel free to contact us at any time if:

  * you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement,
  * you would like to terminate your registration with our Site,
  * you wish to access and/or correct your personal information,
  * you no longer wish to receive promotional material from HHM,
  * you wish to withdraw your name from our subscriber promotional list program,
  * you have a complaint about the manner in which HHM treated your personal information.

You can contact us by calling 416-593-9411, e-mailing us at [privacy@hhmedia.com](mailto:privacy@hhmedia.com), accessing the “Contact Us” section on our Website, or writing us at House & Home Media – Privacy Department, 120 – 511 King Street West, Toronto, Ontario, M5V 2Z4.
